foreign
[Music]
scoping review on the role of nutrition
in the development and prevention of
age-related hearing loss screened
thousands of papers and concluded that
diets rich in saturated fats and
cholesterol have deleterious effects on
hearing that could be prevented by lower
consumption the case of the maban noted
before makes for a compelling story but
on what exactly are they basing their
conclusion it's true that in laboratory
animals you can prove it randomize rats
to added saturated fat or chinchillas to
edit dietary cholesterol and scientists
can show atherosclerosis inducing diets
exacerbate in rear damage and hearing
loss even without noise exposure but
that doesn't necessarily mean the same
is true in people there is coach and
epidemiological data for example study
thousands of twins was able to draw a
significant link between a high
cholesterol diet and hearing impairment
in the Blue Mountains hearing study
which enrolled thousands of older men
and women to study age-related hearing
loss dietary cholesterol was the
nutrient component most associated with
hearing loss those eating about two eggs
worth of cholesterol a day had 34
greater odds of hearing loss compared to
those only getting about a single eggs
worth
consistent with a vascular caused those
on statins and particularly those at
higher doses appear to be at lower risk
the researchers suggest that high
cholesterol intake May interfere with
the circulation within the inner ear
itself or atherosclerotic inflammatory
changes could reduce blood flow to the
tiny arteries feeding the inner ear but
how about looking inside the arteries to
see if this is actually true
the extent and severity of coronary
artery disease in the heart is
determined by angiogram was found to
closely correlate to hearing loss since
atherosclerosis is a systemic disease
affecting the entire arterial tree this
has relevance for the arteries feeding
the inner ear the same was found for the
amount of atherosclerotic plaque found
in the carotid arteries in the neck the
greater the plaque the poorer the
hearing and the more plaque they found
the greater risk of further hearing
impairment measured over the subsequent
five years
getting closer but how about the
arteries that directly Supply the inner
ear early autopsy data suggested
sclerotic changes in the blood vessels
of older ears contribute to inner ear
degeneration and these days direct
Imaging studies correlate the degree of
hearing loss with atherosclerotic
narrowing of those inner ear arteries
now all we need is an Interventional
trial to wrap it all up in a bow yes
it's high cholesterol and high saturated
fat diets have been shown to kill off
those critical inner ear cells and cause
hearing loss and lab animals but it's
not like you can lock hundreds of people
up for a few years and force them to eat
different amounts of saturated fat and
see what happens to their hearing oh but
you can and they did The Finnish mental
hospital study in 1960 one of two Mental
Hospitals near Helsinki had their menus
changed to decrease their intake of
saturated animal fat then after a few
years the two hospitals switched their
menus over it was one of the first
Interventional Trials of its kind
suggesting that you could decrease heart
disease deaths by decreasing saturated
fat intake ah but what happened to their
hearing it followed the exact same
pattern as their heart disease got worse
so did their hearing and then when the
hospital switched the reverse happened
and not just by a little those in their
50s in the lower saturated fat Hospital
ended up with significantly better
hearing than the group in the control
hospital that was 10 years younger the
researchers concluded our audiological
studies lead us to conclude that diet is
an important factor in the prevention of
hearing loss
[Music]
thank you
foreign